# KARA EVANS

kara.e177409@gmail.com · <u>LinkedIn</u> · <u>Portfolio</u> Cleveland, Ohio | *Open to hybrid* & *remote roles*.

#### SUMMARY

Data analyst with over seven years of biomedical industry experience and effective problem-solving skills. Wrote and reviewed investigative reports, reducing backlog by 20% within first year of assignment. Improved and maintained laboratory inventory program, saving company time and money. An adaptable, fast learner who has trained and educated other employees in each professional role.

#### PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

### Senior Laboratory Technologist, Cleveland Cord Blood Center | November 2017-December 2022

- Submitted 5 to 10 investigative reports each week, exceeding the expected goal by 80%.
- Maintained detailed inventory records to track supply counts, product information, and expiration dates, if applicable.
- Developed and improved standard operating procedures to reduce recurring errors.

## Laboratory Technician, Cleveland Clinic | September 2015-November 2017

- Processed large volume of clinical laboratory tests for patient samples with accuracy and efficiency in a team-oriented setting.
- Resolved problems involving patient samples and communicated updates to hospital staff in a timely manner.

#### Analyst, CWM Environmental | August 2014-September 2015

• Performed environmental analysis on industrial waste samples within client-specific deadlines.

#### **EDUCATION**

#### Bachelor of Science, Biological Sciences, Certificate in Environmental Studies, Ohio University | May 2014

## PROJECTS & SKILLS

#### **Staffing Allocation Plan**

Performed data cleansing and integration techniques on multiple data sets to assist a staffing agency with distributing medical staff throughout the United States. Examined trends using statistical analyses and visualizations in Tableau. Developed a dashboard to illustrate areas most affected by influenza infections and in need of additional staff.

#### **Customer Analysis**

Conducted exploratory analyses on customer data from an online grocery store to understand customer demographics and behavior. Merged data frames and developed new variables using Python to answer stakeholder questions. Generated visualizations to illustrate relationships between variables. Findings include ideal advertising times and popular products.

#### **Product Analysis**

Evaluated movie rental company data to provide insights prior to the launch of a new video streaming service. Organized and joined data tables in SQL using queries and common table expressions to answer complex business questions. Built visualizations in Tableau. Findings include geographical sales data, customer behavior, and film rental performance.

Skills: Python, SQL, Tableau, Statistical Analysis